Sheldon Callahan

Developer Advocate at Atlassian

Summary

I work in all things media with strong skills in every area. From Webware and Design to Video Production and Animation my work bridges that gap between those worlds. I have worked with and for some of the top Software Companies and Web Firms and a variety of different projects all with stunning results

Specialties: Strategy, SalesForce, Marketo, UI, UX, PHP, XML, JSON, CSS, HTML, Joomla, Drupal, Magento, Programming, Design, Project Management, JavaScript, JQUERY, MYSQL, Flash, AS3, Flex

Experience

Developer Advocate at Atlassian

May 2016 - Present

Executive Director at Shaolin Life

November 2011 - Present

The Shaolin Buddhist Temple and Education Foundation, founded in 2006 by Master Shi Guo Song from Shaolin Monastery (Henan Province China) passed down to Sheldon Callahan (Executive Director) has a mission to preserve and continue the 1,500-year-old tradition of Shaolin. The Foundation exist for the larger San Francisco Bay Area community teaching inner awareness (Ch'an meditation) through movement (Gong Fu and Qi Gong).

Advisor: former (Chief Developer Evangelist)

July 2015 - May 2016 (10 months)

Web Developer at Salesforce.com

January 2014 - March 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Work with marketing product owner to concept, prototype and build web experiences for flagship Salesforce and Dreamforce websites. Weigh in on key development and technology decisions and consult on best practices. Build high end responsive websites and Single Page Applications that integrate with CMS and internal/external API's. Give internal talks on current technology standards and use cases.

Senior Web Developer at ServiceMax

September 2011 - January 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Develop technology strategies to enable front facing marketing website. Architect, develop, and deploy full stack and responsive web technologies. Manage end to end web functions using HTML 5, Javascript, PHP, APEX, Visual Force, MYSQL, and Mongo DB for marketing purposes. Build custom solutions using the force.com and open source platforms. Integrate 3rd party applications and API's for seamless 360 view

marketing campaigns and customer life cycles. Manage projects, contractors, and direct reports to achieve objectives.

WebMaster at MedAmerica

March 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 5 months)

Align web strategy with the strategic goals of the company. Create and maintain and deploy web applications, policies and procedures. Serve markting team as tech, strategy, and implementation consultant. Manage media platforms: Youtube, Brightcove, ..ect to organize video for online usage.

Owner at Ideal Concepts America

November 1996 - 2011 (14 years 2 months)

Director of Web and Media Projects for Publishing Company

Senior Web Developer

April 2009 - September 2009 (5 months)

Instructor at Bay Area Video Coalition

2007 - 2008 (1 year)

Created curriculum and taught classes in Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks, HTML, CSS, Dreamweaver, and Flash

Associate Software Engineer at CBS Interactive

2006 - 2008 (2 years)

Member of the Ad Technology Group

Software Engineer

2006 - 2008 (2 years)

Lab Manager at CCA

2004 - 2006 (2 years)

Education

Salesforce

Cloud Business, 2014

Academy of Art University

Computer Arts, 2002 - 2004

Westwood College of Technology

Graphic Design Multimedia, 1998 - 1999

Shaolin Luohan Institute

Shaolin Disciple, Shaolin Arts, 2008 - 2012

Activities and Societies: Shaolin Qi Gong, Shaolin Kung Fu, Wu Dang 5 Animal Qi Gong, Yang Style Tai Chi Chuan

BAVC

Honors and Awards

1st Place Traditional Hand Forms at the International Chinese Martial Arts TournamentArt, Design, Shaolin Kung Fu, Qi Gong, Tai Chi, Programming, Film, Music.

Sheldon Callahan

Developer Advocate at Atlassian



Contact Sheldon on LinkedIn